[Episode 29]
The sandbag is ready.
It can warm you up.
I'll apply it for you.
I can do it myself.
Director Meng,
since you're the future empress,
do you mean to keep a distance from me?
That's not what I meant.
What's wrong with you?
I just realized how fast things change.
Is the Censorate about to disband?
Look at this.
See how wonderful these gifts are.
No gossipers will dare
to say a single word against our lady now.
Sure, all thanks to the Second Young Master.
He finally shut up those rumor-mongers.
Stop calling him Second Young Master.
He is now Grand Tutor Shen's son-in-law.
But then again,
I've long noticed
that he had feelings for our lady.
Madam.
Zhi Li will be back with Nian.
Go fetch the head of the house.
Tell him not to only focus on the cooking.
Yes.
Nian.
Now that Zhi Li has married you,
there are some things I must say.
No matter what happened before,
from now on, you two must support each other.
Do your best to work on your marriage.
Don't worry, Father.
I will definitely cherish Zhi Li
like the apple of my eye.
I won't let her come to any harm.
Good.
Zhi Li.
Although Nian indulges you in every way,
you've married him,
so you must not waywardly prank Nian again.
Although I dote on you,
I will also stand up for Nian.
Father, I will be a good wife.
Good.
Zhi Li, Nian is the only son in his family.
If you can soon have his child,
it may rest the souls of his late parents.
Father.
Zhi Li loves the sweet and sour ribs
you cooked.
When you have time, you must teach me.
In the future, I'll cook it for Zhi Li.
I should have taught you long ago.
If Zhi Shu heard me say this,
he would get all jealous and compete
with you over who loves Zhi Li more.
Zhi Shu is always competitive.
You know what?
He used to fight with Zhi Li over a pork rib.
Now, with your help,
Zhi Shu won't be able to snatch any away.
Zhi Shu still hasn't returned.
He even missed my wedding with Nian.
He hasn't even sent a letter home.
He is on a mission and can't make it.
When he returns,
we must get together for a drink.
Father.
Get together.
Here.
Father, is your chest hurting again?
Quickly get the medicine.
It's fine.
It's fine. An old ailment.
It sounds ridiculous,
but in the past,
Zhi Shu always made my chest hurt from anger.
Now, I can't even blame it on him.
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty, an urgent letter from Qingzhou.
[Urgent Report:
Mr. Shen Zhi Shu has died from exhaustion.]
Your Majesty!
[Shen Mansion]
You brat, come out here!
I want to speak to you face to face.
Zhi Shu...
While on an official mission,
he encountered danger.
Come out here!
I am a soldier from Qingzhou.
Under General Huo's order,
I escorted Mr. Shen home.
You must be mistaken.
Zhi Shu wouldn't leave us
without even a word.
Zhi Shu...
My son!
Zhi Shu!
Father!
You said you'd give me the other half
of the bronze tally on my birthday.
Unfortunately,
I'm going on a mission,
so I'm afraid I won't make it back in time.
Can I ask for my birthday gift in advance?
What I meant was,
when you can stand on your own
and shoulder your responsibility
as a loyal subject,
you'll get the other half
of the tiger-head tally.
Father, you're too stingy.
I've been asking for the other half
for three years.
If you don't give it to me,
I'll trade this half for liquor money.
I dare you, you brat.
Father, after I trade it for money,
I'll buy you the most expensive liquor.
Before he left,
he happily showed off to me
that he was appointed
as a fourth-rank Supervisory Censor.
He even asked me for a birthday gift.
But I scolded him in case he'd get arrogant.
If I had known it'd be
the last time we'd see each other...
Now, I have no chance
to give this bronze tally to him again.
Zhi Shu promised
that he would prepare for the wedding
and marry me into the family
when he returned.
[Birth Booklet]
Miss Yan, this is your birth booklet.
Please take it back.
[Marriage Contract]
Before he left,
Zhi Shu wrote the marriage contract,
prepared the betrothal gifts,
and begged me
to prepare Three Letters and Six Rites.
He wanted to marry you in a grand manner
when he returned.
Let's see who dares
to lay a finger on her today!
Fu Zhi, sorry I am late.
If I am to marry Fu Zhi,
the Six Rites must be complete,
and the Three Letters shall be in full.
On an auspicious day,
I shall arrive with a great procession
and have Fu Zhi marry into our Shen family
in full ceremony.
I simply cannot believe that Mr. Shen,
surrounded by noble ladies of the capital,
would truly be willing to forsake
such a life of dazzling splendor,
to pledge a lifelong devotion
to a merchant's daughter like me.
What if I cut off all other romantic ties?
Then clean up all your mess
before you come to ask me again.
I promise you.
If I flirt with any woman,
you can just leave me.
Wait for me.
[Shen Zhi Shu]
Zhi Shu and I haven't formally married yet,
but I've already accepted him as my husband.
If you don't mind,
I am willing to be your daughter-in-law.
Don't be silly.
You are in the prime of your youth.
Don't ruin your entire life. Get up.
I have made up my mind.
Unless...
you are unwilling to accept me.
Only now do I truly understand
why Zhi Shu had eyes only for you.
Zhi Shu is quite lucky
to have your sincere love.
Good child, please get up.
Good child, from now on, we are family.
We're family.
Father.
Mother.
Director Meng, don't worry.
This medicine can
make Miss Yan sleep all day soundly.
She hasn't slept the whole journey.
We have to let her rest well in this way.
Miss Meng, how is Ms. Yan?
Isn't that a stupid question?
Just thinking I'll never see Mr. Shen again,
I feel so sad,
let alone Ms. Yan.
Just last month,
Mr. Shen taught us how to make new liquor.
He said he'd taste it after coming back.
Who the hell killed him?
Mr. Shen was also a member of the Censorate.
I will definitely not let him die in vain.
And I will not let you cry all the time.
Your Majesty, your wounds haven't healed yet.
You must stop now.
If the wounds reopen,
the late emperor will blame me.
I am just injured, not dead.
Chief Steward You, let me handle it.
Director Meng, please persuade His Majesty.
He not only keeps practicing with his injury,
but also hasn't eaten anything all day.
Your Majesty, I know how sad you are.
I will avenge Mr. Shen's death.
If you discover old acquaintances of yours
in the Blood Moon Society,
what will you do?
Trust me, Your Majesty.
I get along well with Situ Xue,
but I have a line in my heart.
If the Blood Moon Society harms the people,
I will never let them off.
Your Majesty, your wounds
have not yet healed.
Let me apply medicine for you, Your Majesty.
Your Highness, it's past the hour of Zi.
The contact hasn't arrived yet.
There might be a change.
Wait a little longer.
Your Highness,
the Blood Moon Society is fickle.
Last time, they not only broke the agreement
but also killed our envoy.
Can you trust such untrustworthy people?
Last time, it happened suddenly.
I always feel
there was something fishy about it.
I will personally negotiate
with the Blood Moon Society again.
But your brother
strongly advocates appeasement.
I'm afraid your connection
with the Blood Moon Society...
My brother is quite indecisive
and extremely naive.
He foolishly believes a marriage contract
can bring peace.
When Ying Gua refused a marriage alliance.
Beijian's dignity was already
trampled underfoot.
Wolves do not wag their tails and beg,
while only dogs do.
In the past two years, at the border,
the Ning Empire has increased troops,
stockpiled grain, and fortified cities,
very likely to trap us to death
in the northern desert.
This time, I will show them
what the true armored cavalry is.
I will also prove to my father
that the land is not won
by kneeling and begging,
but by fighting with swords.
Your Highness, someone is coming.
Master.
I've removed the misunderstanding
with the Second Prince of Beijian.
It's been confirmed that someone indeed
impersonated us to sabotage the alliance.
Second Prince of Beijian
has agreed to ally with us
to attack the Ning Empire.
Their blood will not be shed in vain.
The blood debts Ning owes
must be repaid
with countless lives of their people.
Now, their court is in turmoil,
and our princess
is about to reach the peak of power.
Once her memory is awakened,
we will immediately
help our princess restore our land!
Help our princess restore our land!
[Spirit Tablet of Shen Zhi Shu]
[Shen Mansion]
Master, Master Zhi Shu's spirit has returned.
Father, Mother,
I'm back.
Zhi Shu.
Sorry, I made you worry.
My son!
It's good that you're back.
Master.
Fu Zhi.
Shen Zhi Shu...
How could you?
Do you know how much spirit money
I've burned for you?
Do you know how heartbroken I was?
How can you joke about life and death?
Let me see.
It will scare you.
Father.
Are you disappointed in me?
Throughout your life,
you've made so many achievements.
I'm afraid
I'll never be able to do better than you.
The only thing to be proud of
was my handsome face.
Sadly, I've lost the only advantage.
As the eldest son of the family,
you've kept His Majesty company
since childhood.
At the age of 20, you became an official
through our family's prestige.
Compared to the hard-working scholars,
you're quite fortunate.
But facing great honor and favor,
you can't be weak
academically or physically.
As His Majesty's trusted friend,
you must not have great ambition for power,
nor can you be completely unambitious.
More importantly,
you shoulder the heavy responsibility
of continuing the glory of the entire family.
I was extremely tough on you
just in case you'd get complacent
with even small achievements.
So I...
I constantly suppressed you.
After hearing the news about you,
I've always wanted to tell you
that I'm proud of you.
I was wrong.
I never expected
to hear an old fogey like you apologize.
If I had come back half a month later,
wouldn't you have given me the entire family?
You...
You brat!
It must have hurt badly.
Compared to when you used to spank me before,
this little pain is nothing.
Although I was injured, I was also lucky.
I took the Blood Moon Society's token
and was rescued by a member of them.
While recovering in the Blood Moon Society,
I got important information.
Mr. Shangguan is not only alive,
but also hiding right within the court.
I should have expected
that he wouldn't die that easily.
Your Majesty,
are you going to immediately investigate?
But if handled improperly,
there will surely be infighting.
And when the Blood Moon Society
and Beijian join forces,
the whole country will be
under attack from inside and out.
But the First Prince of Beijian
proposed a marriage alliance,
which means a betrayal
to the Blood Moon Society.
So Mr. Shangguan is colluding
with the Second Prince.
Very likely.
I heard the Second Prince has been
at odds with his brother.
And he is more of a warmonger
compared to his brother.
He is quite cunning
and must be guarded against.
Regardless, Your Majesty,
if you reject the marriage alliance,
I'm afraid war will be unavoidable.
The whole land was won through fights.
The two princes are both very cunning
and ambitious.
Since they secretly colluded
with the Blood Moon Society,
I don't believe they will keep any promise.
He has proposed a marriage alliance
merely because he fears our border cavalry.
The misunderstanding
between Beijian and the Blood Moon Society
will be removed sooner or later.
My father once said
that Beijian is ambitious and cunning.
I'm ready to go to battle at any time.
But before that, we must find Shangguan.
I suspect
that Shangguan is close to us.
When I first came here with Your Majesty,
I was not an official yet.
I boldly asked Your Majesty
for a post in the Censorate.
I was even scolded by Your Majesty for it.
I still remember how bold you were.
And I knew the position was destined for you.
Now,
you've indeed fulfilled your promise.
You have even done better
than I expected.
When I was a new official,
I was almost alone.
Fu Zhi was the only person I cared about.
That's why I had no scruples.
I never hesitated at all to dig up corpses,
investigate cases, and handle Ling Yun Fei.
But now,
there are more people I want to protect.
So I have learned what fear is.
We are all afraid of losing.
During this period of time,
I've helplessly watched those close to me
depart one after another.
Zhi Shu's incident
scared me even more.
I rule the entire land,
yet I'm afraid
I cannot protect those I care about.
I will never leave you, Your Majesty.
I wish to continue working
in the Censorate for Your Majesty.
Meng Ting Hui.
Let's get married.
Now that the situation is stable,
no one can stop us anymore.
I personally made this hairpin
for three months,
hoping to put up your hair
and crown you with it
in front of the whole country.
Your Majesty,
I cannot marry you now.
Why not?
Your Majesty, you know me.
I've done it all
to tackle the ills in the country.
The Blood Moon Society intends
to overthrow the entire country.
What terrifies me even more is
that Shangguan is lurking right in the court.
So Your Majesty,
please allow me
to investigate the Blood Moon Society.
Anything else is fine,
but not the Blood Moon Society.
I've entrusted the investigation
entirely to Zhi Shu.
Your Majesty,
you're hiding something from me.
I used to ask Your Majesty
if we were already honest with each other.
Turns out
we're not yet.
I have to be wary of anything
related to the country.
Even with you,
I cannot be completely honest.
I will take my leave.
[Shen Mansion]
[Integrity of Pine and Bamboo]
Shen Zhi Shu,
how long are you going to hide from me?
Fu Zhi, let's break up.
Don't come anymore.
Break up?
You personally wrote the marriage contract.
Are you not going to honor it?
I failed to keep my promise.
My body now has scars.
Even my face...
It's just scars.
Be a real man and hold your head high.
What's the big deal?
I actually think
that with this scar,
you look even more manly.
I'm serious.
As a subject,
I've long put life and death out of my mind.
Now, since our country is in a crisis,
internally and externally,
our family bears heavy responsibilities.
Maybe on an official mission,
I won't just get injured.
I'll wait for you to come back then.
No matter what,
I can wait for you my whole life.
I like the charming gentleman
who was drunk
and picked flowers for me before.
But right now,
I ache more
for the man standing right before me
with a scar on his face.
He is worth loving for a lifetime.
[Lovesickness]
Meng, His Majesty treats you quite well.
He specially allowed you to bathe here.
Not to mention, for your sake,
he even abolished the ancestral precepts.
It's simply enviable.
Since when did you become his advocate?
He has even bought my best friend.
Nobody backs me up now.
Dear Meng,
no matter what happens in the future,
I will be on your side.
I don't care about any so-called principle.
What I care about is only you.
However,
I think of all men in this world,
only His Majesty is perfect for you.
I know what you've been through.
So I hope someone can protect you.
Fu Zhi.
Marrying His Majesty
means placing myself under the scrutiny
of the entire country.
If I become the empress,
even if I advise him once,
all court officials will say
I interfere in politics.
What I want is not the glory of the empress,
but clear and upright governance.
I want him to be a good ruler.
But I also don't want
to give up my aspirations
or get trapped within the harem.
I understand completely.
But do you really not want to marry him?
Alright, I won't say anymore.
Let's not talk about what's troubling you.
Now, let's just relax.
Meng, when did you get a mark on your body?
What mark?
It looks like a bird.
It's red.
A red bird?
This mark on your back is unique.
Which one are you referring to?
Do you know this image?
Yao.
Shangguan.
This is my father's Black Bird.
It's the most powerful divine bird.
Please, draw one for me too.
Draw one even bigger than the Black Bird.
No, you must draw it for me first.
I want a red bird.
He won't draw it for you.
- He is mine.
- No, he's not!
My father said
Shangguan will be my husband in the future.
Shangguan is mine!
Yao, hurry!
Someone's over there. Chase them!
Are you alright?
Shangguan, your hand!
Keep your voice down.
Where is Xi Xia?
She died for you.
Yao, remember, you must live.
Forget today. Forget who you are.
Retreat! Quickly retreat!
Shangguan!
What happened?
What's wrong?
Your Majesty, let's get married.
Have you thought this through?
I don't want you to force yourself.
By the mandate of heaven,
I rule over the land.
Meng Ting Hui is valiant,
virtuous, and upright.
I hereby make her empress of the country.
Relevant offices choose an auspicious day
and prepare the Six Rites.
I'll personally ride the imperial carriage
and escort her into the palace.
Relevant officials apply the decree.
Yin Qing.
[Records of Mountains and Rivers]
Over the last three years,
I have never noticed this scar on your hand.
You've been focused on fighting evil.
You never care about trivial things.
But everything is about timing.
It's not too late to see it now.
- Some choices could have been--
- Once I have made choices,
I will not change my mind.
The third chapter of this new book records
that after the completion of water projects
in the seven prefectures,
grain production increased by 30 percent.
Have you read it?
I just wonder if that 30 percent of grain
is enough to feed those laborers
who dug the canals and built the dikes.
Beneath prosperity, there are always shadows.
In recent years,
the country has been peaceful and prosperous.
Peaceful and prosperous?
But blood and tears are erased from the book.
The peace on paper is built
on countless corpses.
I am in the Ning Empire.
As a citizen,
I watch the country grow increasingly strong
and prosperous.
As a subject,
I witness how hard His Majesty works
to make people live and work in peace.
The true peace we seek will come
in the not-too-distant future.
But what about those
who cannot wait until then?
I believe
the sky will clear up after the rain.
The Rain Bell,
in essence, creates an illusion.
If you look at it for a while,
you'll actually forget
that the rain has never stopped.
Even the rainbow is fake.
Meng.
You remain calm even in big trouble.
Now, you actually seem nervous.
After all, she's marrying His Majesty.
If she says she's not nervous,
I won't believe it.
Come on. Tonight, let's get drunk.
Cheers.
- Cheers.
- Alright.